一定有其他解释
There must be someother explanation.
我有个主意－咱们去散步好吗?
I have an idea - shallwe go for a walk?
当婚姻没有爱时会有无婚姻的爱
When there's marriage without love,there'll be love without marriage.
但Robert和我是因爱而结合的...
But Robert and I marriedfor love...
当然，我也曾是的
Of course. And so did I.
但当热情逝去后...
But before the year was over...
Benito开始摆弄各式衬裙
Benito was lifting all kindsof petticoats.
我不得已辞去了最好的女佣
I had to dismiss my best maid.
不，我想起来了
No, no, I remember.
我把她送给了我的表亲
I passed her on tomy cousin.
她丈夫很短视，我觉得
Her husband was soshort-sighted, I thought.
他好像是循着气味查的
But he navigated by scent,it seems.
真不幸
So unfortunate.
相信我，这我们都经历过
Believe me, darling,it happens to us all.
不死的爱就象你别墅里的鬼魂
Undying love is like theghost in your villa.
人们都谈论...
Everybody talks about it...
但试试去找一个得到的人吧
but try and find one personwho has seen it.
- 你能帮我个忙吗?- 任何事
- Can I ask you a favour?- Anything at all.
关于Erlynne太太...
About, Mrs Erlynne...
很聪明的女人
Very clever woman.
她昨晚把我扔出来了
She threw me out last night.
知道了我有多蠢知道的跟我自己一样清楚
Knows what a fool I am.Knows it as well as I do myself.
她会在这跟我碰面喝茶
She's meeting me herefor tea, though.
能跟一个完全理解我的女人走到一起真是太棒了
It's a great thing to come across awoman who thoroughly understands me.
今晚别带她到我们的舞会你会介意吗?
Would you mind not bringingher to our party tonight?
这是你要的帮忙吗?
That's the favour?
Meg 觉得那样会使事情变的不舒服
Meg feels it might makethings awkward.
那么是真的喽?
So it's true, then?
我不相信，你不是那个类型
I don't believe it.You don't seem the type.
尽管我会说Erlynne太太实在迷人难以抗拒，但是……
Though I will say Mrs Erlynne's damnfascinating. Hard to resist, but...
你不是认真的，对吧?
You're not serious, are you?
我警告你，你得跟我决斗才能抢她
I warn you, you'll have tofight me for her.
而我可是个坠入爱河的男人
And I'm a man in love.
你说什么呢?
What are you talking about?
这边请，Erlynne太太
This ways, Mrs Erlynne.
- 多谢- 不客气
- Thanks.- You're welcome.
- 跟我来- 你往哪里带我?
- Come with me.- Where are you taking me?
- 放开我的手- 我非跟你谈谈不可
- Let go of my arm.- I have to talk to you.
我要见Augustos大人
I'm meeting Lord Augustos.
你马上得离开Amalfi
You must leave Amalfi at once.
去哪?你已经替我付了一个季的租金
And go where? You've paid myrent here for the season.
我会付其他地方的帐我要你上明天第一班飞机
I'll pay it somewhere else. I wantyou on the first plane out tomorrow.
- 我不理解- 人们在谈论
- I don't understand.- People are talking.
我们
About us.
我不觉得可笑
I don't see the humour.
在这里，埋葬一个秘密会冒出另一个假的吗？
Bury a real secret anda false one pops up in its place?
你得承认确实这么荒谬
There's a certain irony,you have to admit.
我不想走，在这挺高兴的
I'm not ready to leave.I'm enjoying myself here.
我恳求你
I'm begging you.
想想Meg，如果她知道你是她妈妈...
Think of Meg. If she knew thatyou were her mother...
那会毁灭她的
it would destroy her.
Meg, 高尚的Windemeres?
Meg, of the magnificentWindemeres?
家族丑闻对一个有抱负的政治家是不健康的
Family scandal is unhealthyfor aspiring politicians.
我不是这屋里唯一一个爱管闲事的人
I'm not the only pragmatistin this room.
爱管闲事? 20年，音讯全无
Pragmatist? Twenty years,and not a word.
当她嫁入豪门时你倒出现了
You turn up when she marriesa man with money.
你管那叫爱管闲事？我有更好的形容方法
You call that pragmatism?I can think of other words.
你想伤害我的感情吗?
Are you trying to hurtmy feelings?
你有感情吗？那是不能买卖的
Do you have any? That can'tbe purchased, I mean.
多少钱，能让你坐上头班机走开?
How much - to get youon the first flight out?
我觉得每次他吻我都是不洁的
I feel every time he'skissed me it's filthy.
我们在一起的每分钟都是谎言
A lie, every minute we'vebeen together.
他怎么能呢?
How could he?
每个男人生来都说实话但死时都是骗子
Every man is born truthfuland every man dies a liar.
现在，无论你做什么都不能引人注目
Now, whatever you do, youmustn't make a scene.
太令人不快而且也浪费你的精力
It's too unpleasant.And you waste your energy.
当然不会
No, of course not. I wouldn't.
哭是平庸女人的庇护所
Crying is the refugeof plain women.
漂亮女人去购物
Pretty women go shopping.
上那班飞机我会把现金奉上
Be on that plane.I'll send the cash.
我没听错吧?
Did I hear you correctly?
Meg Windemere 是你的女儿?
That Meg Windemere isyour daughter?
我女儿?
My daughter?
Robert的妻子?
Robert's wife?
你怎么敢
How dare you.
她至少有20岁了，她的妈妈?
She must be twenty at least.Her mother?
我真的看上去有那么老吗?
Do I look as old as all that?
当然不是
Of course not.
我一定是在打盹
I must have nodded off.
你困了，回去接着睡吧
You were dozing.Go back to sleep.
快点
Come on.
今晚不谈生意，我们改天再谈
No business tonight.We can talk another day.
-高兴见到你-晚会真好
- Good to see you.- Lovely party.
再来点香槟
More champagne.
欢迎，好好玩
Welcome.Have a great party.
- 晚上好，Dumby先生- 哦，晚上好，Stutfield太太
- Good evening, Mr Dumby.- Oh, good evening, Mrs Stutfield.
这一季最后的晚会了吧
Last party of the season,I suppose.
- 真令人愉快，是吧?- 非常令人愉快
- It's been delightful, hasn't it?- Quite delightful.
晚上好，这里，是本季最后的晚会了
Good evening. Here it is,the last party of the season.
我猜也是，尽管是个闷人的季节是吧？
I suppose so. It's been a very dullseason, though, hasn't it?
闷人，是啊，很闷
Dull. Yes, terribly dull.
－晚安, Cecil- 你好, Dumby
- Evening, Cecil.- Hello, Dumby.
我希望这是本季最后的晚会了
I suppose this'll be the lastparty of the season.
肯定不是，至少还会有两个
Surely not. Probablybe two more at least.
我今天做了个怪透了的梦
I had the oddest dream today.
刚刚想起了一小部分...
A bit of it has justcome back to me...
我们喝什么呢?
So what are we drinking?
- 生日女郎在哪里?- 正在变形
- Where's the birthday girl?- Transforming herself.
香肠和女人
Sausages and women.
如果你想享受她们...
If you want to enjoy theexperience...
千万别看过程
never watch thepreparation of either.
- 那是新的吗?- 刚出盒，你喜欢吗?
- Is that new?- Just out of the box. Do you like it?
你会有点冷，我给你拿个披肩吧
You might be a little cold.I'll get you a wrap.
毁掉线条吗，你朋友没教你意大利时装吗?
And spoil the lines? Didn't your friendteach you about Italian fashion?
我朋友?
My friend?
我看见支票了，少来...
I saw the cheques. Don't even...
Plymdale女士, 你来真好
Lady Plymdale, so good ofyou to come.
再要一杯香槟吗?
Do you want another glass ofchampagne?
我俩都来点吧
Let's get us both some.
你怎么给我问安?
Why don't you ask me how I am?
我喜欢人给我问安
I like people to ask.
表示对我健康的普遍关心
It shows a widespreadinterest in my health.
你不会知道那让人多舒服
And you can't imagine howcomforting that is.
晚会不错
Lovely party.
- 你好, Cecil?- 一点都不好
- How are you, Cecil?- Oh, not well at all.
我希望Alessandra...
I'd like Alessandra...
认识一下从澳洲来的Hopper先生
to know Mr. Hopperfrom Australia.
- 你可以介绍一下吗?- 请容我一点时间好吗?
- Would you introduce her?- Would you just excuse me for a moment?
跟Windemere先生走谢谢
Go with Mr Windemere.Thank you.
她是我最小的，我会想她的
She's my last, you know.I will miss her.
但是在她们开始攻击你之前...
But it's best to get them outof the nest...
还是把她们从巢里赶走吧
before they turn on you.
女孩最初是爱妈妈的但长大后就会评价你
Girls begin by loving their mothers.But as they grow they judge us.
很少会宽容
Rarely do they forgive us.
哦，可怜的傻子就是学不会
Oh, poor fool.He'll never learn.
那个傻子？别让我选
Which fool?Don't make me choose.
Tuppy,他把Erlynne太太带来了
Tuppy,he's brought Mrs Erlynne.
所有女人都会怠慢她
All the women will snub her.
她跟男人在一起没准会有点运气
She may have betterluck with the men.
那是因为男人...
It is because of men...
女人才不信任女人
that women distrust other women.
女人不信女人,男人也不信女人...
Women don't trust women,men don't trust women...
没人相信女人
no-one trusts women.
就是这个联合了印度教和天主教
It's what binds the Hinduand the Catholic.
我知道我发过誓但我必需说你今晚真美
I know I promised, but I must tellyou how beautiful you look tonight.
好吧，如果你非说就说吧
Well, if you must, you must.
请原谅，我在找其他人
I beg your pardon, I waslooking for someone else.
而你找到了我
Well, you found me.
Erlynne太太
Mrs Erlynne.
我可以叫你Stella吗？
May I call you Stella?
Augustus大人给我拿香槟去了
Lord Augustus is gettingme champagne.
你和我可以交换恩宠
You and I can trade favours.
很诱人，但算了
Tempting, but no.
我宁愿他不会看到月光下的我们或许会令他误解
I'd rather he didn't see us under themoonlight. He might misunderstand.
听我说
Hear me out.
Windemere财富胜过Tuppy
Windemere's fortune exceeds Tuppy's.
干嘛现在换马?
Why change horses now?
你得到所要的，Meg也自由了
You can have waht youwant and Meg's free.
自由?
Free?
她没有离开他的勇气
She hasn't the courage to leave him.
但如果明确了他跟你在一起...
But if it's clear to her thathe's with you...
他没有
He's not.
你买的谣言不可靠，赶紧去退款吧
You've been buying idle gossip.You should get a refund.
请原谅
Excuse me.
我非邀请她不可, Dumby
I had to invite her, Dumby.
问题是，她变了你可以从她眼睛里看出来
The point is, she's a changed woman.You can see it in her eyes.
你以为你要是穷她会看你一眼吗?
Do you think she'd look atyou if you were poor?
那你以为如果她丑我会看她吗?
Do you think I'd look at herif she were ugly?
公平是公平，互利互惠
Fair's fair, exchange ratesand so forth.
我知道她有点这有点那...
I know she's had her thisand her that, but...
但如果男人能有过去...
if a man can toleratehis own past...
他妻子干嘛不能有?而且肯出钱...
Why not a past in his wife?At any rate...
什么都能擦干净重新开始
it's wipe the slate.Clean start.
她和我……我们可以互相理解
She and I, we...understand each other.
你知道他们怎么说
And you know what they say.
每个圣人都有个过去而每个罪人都有个未来
Every saint has past,every sinner has a future.
如果她肯要，我想向她求婚
I'm going to ask her to marryme if she'll have me.
你知道人们为什么称之为圣坛, Tuppy?
You know why they call itan altar, Tuppy?
因为那里以人为祭祀
It's where they makehuman sacrifices.
我今天梦到 Erlynne太太
I had a dream aboutMrs Erlynne today.
是吗...
Yes, well...
你是情不自禁吧...
you couldn't help it,I suppose. She...
她真了不起
she is quite the woman.
但以后……
But in future...
还是请梦别人去吧
please try to dream ofsomeone else.
你不觉得自己喝够了吗?
Don't you think you'vehad enough?
- 晚会很好- 谢谢赏光
- Lovely party.- Thanks for coming.
Meg?
我得去换衣服
I have to change.
- 你看见她了吗?- 没有
- Did you see her?- Don't.
你很可爱
You're lovely.
她那岁数的女人穿真荒唐
It's ridiculous on a woman at her age.
你干嘛不告诉我?
Why didn't you tell me?
你说过你是我的朋友
You said you were my friend.
男女之间无法成朋友
Men and women can't be friends.
- Meg?- 不
- Meg?- No.
你能跟他在一起吗?
Can you stay with him?
你今晚能跟他上床吗?
Can you get into bedwith him tonight?
明晚?以后呢？
Tomorrow night?Nights after that?
你自己说的，男人背叛妻子不可原谅
You said yourself, there's noforgiving a man who betrays his wife.
你怎么选?
What will you choose?
一个虚伪可耻的婚姻还是一个没有妥协的真我？
A false degrading marriage, or yourown true self, free of compromise?
我对你一见钟情，这是真的
I've loved you from the beginning.It's the truth.
你在手套店抽出手来的那刻我想“就是她了”
Moment you held out your hand to me inthe glove shop, I thought 'there she is".
那时，我是否该不加停留的离去呢?
And then, suppose I'd walkedby without stopping?
只那样一想
Just the thought of it.
至今我从未爱过
I've never loved anyone until now.
停
Stop.
John?
对不起，我不想吓你
I'm sorry, I didn't meanto startle you.
我在找Meg，你看见她了吗？
I'm looking for Meg. If you see her,it's important.
你排队了吗?
Have you had a row?
一个小舞会
A little misunderstanding.
看看酒吧
Try the bar.
Tuppy为她戒烟了
Tuppy's given up smokes for her.
女人
Women.
Women 给我们向上的灵感
Women inspire us to great things.
却又不明所以地阻止我们实施
Then somehow prevent usfrom doing any of them.
他向她求婚了
He's proposing to her.
该是他第三次上圣坛了
It will be his third time up the aisle.
希望是个制胜之举， Dumby
Hope trumps experience, Dumby.
是人类竞争中上帝之玩笑而已
It's God's joke on the human race.
他确信她已改过自新了
He's quite convinced she'schanged her spots.
想把那变有趣吗?
Care to make it interesting?
告诉你我是认真的了
I told you I was serious.
没有人警告你该反对我吗?
Hasn't anyone warned youagainst me?
哦，是的，所有人
Oh, yes. Everyone.
把它拿开
Put it away.
你并不用马上就爱上我
Now, you don't have to loveme right away.
想想钱
Think of the money.
假设我跟你结婚一年内你的投资缩水了
Suppose I marry you, and in a yearyour investments go sour.
我就被个叫花子栓住了
I'll be stuck with a pauper.
另一个情形是...
On the other hand...
我可能下礼拜二死在高尔夫球场……
I could drop dead on the golf coursenext Tuesday...
而你可就富裕了
and you'd be left verywell-appointed.
生命就是赌博, Stella
Life's a gamble, Stella.
我不知如何作答
I don't know what to say.
人讲太多话
People say too much as it is.
Windemere太太跟Erlynne太太...
Mrs Windemere andMrs Erlynne...
看起来就跟母女是的，是吧?
Iook like mother and daughter,don't they?
他们穿着同样的衣服
They're wearing the same dress.
就是的
Well, that'll be it.
跟我走吧
Come away with me.
我们今晚就出海
We could set sail tonight.
求你
Please.
这是你开玩笑的方式吗？
Is this your idea of a joke?
我得跟你谈谈Darlington
I need to speak to you.It's about Darlington.
跟我来
Follow me.
他爱上Meg了
He's in love with Meg.
我知道我说到钱的问题，我要提高数目让你现在就走
I know we said cash, so I'm raisingthe amount. I want you to leave now.
我要是你会更小心的
I'd be more concernedif I were you.
你不是我
You're not me.
问题是我对我妻子说谎了...
The problem is I've beenlying to my wife...
而我很不在行
and I'm not very good at it.
我可以再添加谣言...
I can add up the rumours...
让她看什么都没有我是Tuppy的女人
and show her a big fat zero.I'm Tuppy's girl.
- 案件结束了- 我自己会解释，你出去吧
- Case closed.- I'll do my own explaining, get out.
我要跟她道别
I'd like to say goodbye to her.
你20年前就跟她道别了没有选择余地
You said goodbye to her twentyyears ago. No second chances.
我先离开
I'll leave first.
- 我们不该一起出去- 你是专家
- We shouldn't walk out together.- You're the expert.
数100下
Count to a 100.
Windemere太太?
Mrs Windemere?
亲爱的Robert, 我以为我们的婚姻是完美的
Dear Robert, I thought ourmarriage was perfect.
我以为我们永远会在一起
I thought we wouldalways be together.
如果你爱Erlynne太太,你该跟他在一起
If you love Mrs Erlynne,you should be with her.
我觉得真愚蠢
I feel so foolish.
每个人都知道，只有我不知道
Everyone knew but me.
Meg, 让我进去我要跟你谈谈
Meg, let me in,I wanna talk to you.
请开门
Please, open the door.
我和Stella Erlynne之间什么都没有
There is nothing between meand Stella Erlynne.
你怎么能那么想?
How can you think it?
上帝她那么老，还染头发
She's old for God's sake.She dyes her hair.
她象印度人一样粉刷她的脸
She paints her facelike an Indian.
她是个冷血自私的女人
She's a cold,selfish woman.
如果你认识她就知道她根本不吸引人
Not all attractiveonce you know her.
她想毁灭一个人
Look, she was goingto damage someone.
一个不会伤害她的人
A person who'd never doneher any harm.
她带来的秘密会伤你的心
She came here with a secret thatwould have broken your heart.
我想告诉你，但不知如何做
Look, I wanted to tell you. I justdidn't know how.
我是想保护你，你得相信我
I was trying to protect you,you have to believe me.
她管我要钱，我给了她...
She asked me for moneyand I gave it to her, but...
我并不以被勒索而自豪...
I'm not proud ofbeing blackmailed...
我不知所措
I didn't know what else to do.
我该开始就告诉你的
I should have told youat the start.
我不打算再骗你了...
I'm not lying to you now, I...
我爱你
I love you.
我心里没有别人...
And there's no otherwoman in my heart...
床上也没有
or in my bed.
Meg...
请开门
please open the door.
我俩都喝太多香槟了
We both had toomuch champagne.
我们明早再谈吧
We can talk in the morning.
- 太棒了- 谢谢你来
- Splendid.- Thank you for coming.
- 晚会不错， Robert.- 我们在俱乐部见
- Lovely party. Goodnight, Robert.- I'll see you at the club.
- 女孩在这里啊-带Windemere去俱乐部
- There's the girl.- Take Windemere to the club.
整晚守着他，如果能就灌醉他
Keep him out all night.Get him drunk if you have to.
- 就是别让他回家- 为什么?
- Just don't let him come home.- Why?
什么啊？
What? What?
我喜欢你，真的
I like you, I do.
但是如果想奏效的话，你就不能那样
But if this is going to workbetween us, you can't do that.
- 哪样？- “哪里？什么？为什么”
- Do what?- "Where? What? Why?"
我不能老解释跟...
I can't always explainmyself to myself...
别人解释自己
let alone anyone else.
不错，放开压力
Good for you -takes the pressure off.
9成的男人...
Nine times out of ten, mendon't give two pins about why...
无法接受被强加的兴趣
they just feel obligedto take an interest.
那么我就按吩咐行事...
So, I'll do exactly as you wish...
假装感觉我们已经结婚了
and I'll feel as ifwe're married already.
哦，你能安全回家吗?
Oh, can you get yourselfhome all right?
哇, Tuppy...
Why, Tuppy...
你是第一个这么问我的男人
you're the first man who'sasked me that.
我不必是第一个Stella，就当最后一个吧
I don't need to be the first,Stella. Just the last.
在码头上有辆出租车等着
There's a taxi waitingat the end of the dock.
我丈夫让你来的
My husband sent you.
你丈夫以为你喝了一瓶矿泉水...
Your husband thinks you'rein bed sleeping off...
已经睡了
a litre of Perrier Jouet.
走吧
Let's go.
他给我钱了，就这样
He gave me money,that's all.
我是家族的老朋友
I'm an old friend of the family.
你以为我傻吗?
Do you think I'm stupid?
嫁给了一个爱的人，又跟...
Married to man you loveand running off...
一个国际花花公子离家?我以为你傻?
with an international playboy?Do I think you're stupid?
这跟你无关
This is none of your business.
你以为开衩变高了，我们可以投票...
You think because hems are higherand women can vote...
一切就会为我们而改变吗?
that anything hasreally changed for us?
朋友们会不跟你联系
Friends will stop calling.
他会受邀回家，而你不会
He'll be invited into homesyou're not.
你可以做到
You manage.
别吓比较
Don't compare yourself.
无悔的生活需要准备和练习
It takes practice andskill to live without regret.
一段婚姻需要你整个心灵
A marriage takesyour whole heart.
自私的人做不到，但你不是
Selfish people can't pull it off,but you're not that.
我们都失败了你也不会
You can succeed wherethe rest of us fail.
- 我干嘛要信你?- 别信我，信他
- Why should I believe you?- Don't believe me, believe him.
他对你是忠诚的，我以性命担保
He's been faithful to you,I'll swear it on my life.
他让你撒谎
He told you to lie.
他甚至不知道你在这
He doesn't evenknow you're here.
他不必知道
He never has to know.
你让我再撒谎吗?
You want me to lie again?
我们间的一切都完了，我不能
Everything's spoiledbetween us. I can't.
你怎么了?
What's happened to you?
谁教你这么不能宽容?
Who taught you to be sounforgiving?
你犯了个错，别再犯了
You made a mistake,don't make it worse.
你对不完美的东西熟视无睹...
You shut your eyes to everythingthat isn't perfect...
你被带向一个陷阱
you're just asking to fallinto a hole.
好吧
Fine.
去吧
Go ahead.
放弃爱而选择傲慢和内疚吧
Step over love to pick uppride and guilt.
真是20岁这一年里
What will that tradebe worth in a year?
最赔了买卖了
In twenty?
Darlington, 你的船非得这么大吗?
Darlington, does your boatreally have to be so big?
你知道人们怎么议论有大船的男人吗？
You know what they say aboutmen with big boats.
- 我得回家了- 你得抽支雪茄，真的?
- I should be getting home.- You'll take a cigar, surely?
我以为你放弃对好女人的爱了呢
I thought you'd quitfor the love of a good woman.
好女人可不是 Erlynne太太的名字
Good woman isn't exactly themoniker I'd choose for Mrs Erlynne.
你在暗示她是魔鬼的侍女吗？
You imply she'sthe devil's handmaiden.
Dumby和我正为你的未来担忧呢
Dumby and I are just concernedfor your future.
魔鬼般的女人是麻烦好女人又太闷了
Devilish women are a bother,and good ones are a bore.
那是唯一的不同
That's the only difference.
Erlynne太太即不是麻烦也不是沉闷
Mrs Erlynne is neither a bothernor a bore.
你改变了习惯但我怀疑她也会改变
You change your habits,but I doubt she'll change hers.
我跟 Dumby 赌了50块
I've bet Dumby fifty quid.
够了
Enough of this.
我不想听反对她的话了
I won't hear any more wordssaid against her.
她是我对女人一切愿望的完美体现
She's everything I've everwanted in a woman.
我亲爱的Tuppy,这世界上只有两个惨剧
My dear Tuppy, in this worldthere are only two tragedies.
一是一无所获，一是得偿所愿
One is not getting what one wants,the other is getting it.
后者是最差的，真正的惨剧
The last is very much the worst.The last is a real tragedy.
婚姻
Marriage.
痛苦万分，问Edna
It has its pains - ask Edna.
单身生活没乐趣
Celibacy has no pleasures.
- 你怎么知道?- 我可以学
- What would you know about it?- I can learn.
来证明我的爱
If it will prove my love.
女人需要验证?
A woman who needs proof?
在她离开她丈夫以前
Before she'll leave her husband.
John,你是个无赖
John, you are a cad.
我们都在臭水沟里
We're all in the gutter.
而我们中的一些人却在看星星
But some of us are lookingat the stars.
男人称它为“殷勤”
What men call gallantry...
上帝称它为“通奸”
ans God's adultery...
这种事在天气闷热的地方，尤其容易发生
is far more common where the climate's sultry.
那是我买给Meg的
That's the one I bought Meg.
生日礼物
For her birthday.
你肯定吗?
Are you sure?
必是上次你来吃饭时她落在这的
She must have left it last weekwhen you came for lunch.
可她今晚拿着来着
She was carrying it tonight.
扇子彼此相象
One fan looks very muchlike another.
John?
- 我不知道- Meg不是在这里吧?
- I've no idea.- Meg's not here, is she?
当然不是
No, of course not.
- 那是什么?- 我什么都没听见
- What's that?- I didn't hear anything.
她在楼下
She's downstairs.
冷静你喝太多了...
Calm down.You've had too much...
别让你自己出丑
Don't make an ass of yourself.
太晚了
Too late.
- 该死- 你弄点冰敷上吧
- Bloody hell!- You better put some ice on that.
我以为是我的呢
I thought it was mine.
肯定是误拿了Windemere的
I must have picked upMrs Windemere's by mistake.
Tuppy, 我发誓，我不知道
Tuppy, I swear, I had no idea.
你欠Cecil 50磅，对不起
You owe Cecil fifty quid. Sorry.
好像是我出丑了Windemere，不是你
It seems I'm the ass,Windemere. Not you.
我在John船上过的夜
I spent the night on John's boat.
我喝多了
I had too much to drink.
你能原谅我吗?
Can I ask you to forgive me?
我昨夜做了很蠢的事
I did something very stupidlast night.
你不是我的同伙
You're not in my league.
我出了大丑
I made a complete ass of myself.
毁了Tuppy
Ruined it for poor Tuppy.
但我想这迟早会发生
Better now than later, I guess.
Tuppy?
他取消了向Erlynne太太求婚
His engagement toMrs Erlynne is off.
你说什么呢?
What are you talking about?
昨晚在John游艇上，Erlynne在他卧室里等他
Last night on John's yacht, MrsErlynne was waiting in his bedroom.
看，我喝多了，我以为...
Look, I was drunk, I thought...
我看见了你的扇子，我以为...
I saw your fan, I thought that...
我没用脑子
I didn't think.
是她
It was her.
她说是她误拿了
She said she took it by mistake.
- 不，那不是事实- 当然不是
- No, that's not true.- Oh, of course not.
最好数数勺子
Better count the spoons.
你不让她来是对的
You were rightnot to want her here.
我对John期望挺高的，Tuppy可是他的朋友啊
I'd have expected more from John,though. Tuppy's his friend.
她没拿我的扇子，我把它...
She didn't take my fan.I left it on the...
有美国的电话
There's a telephone callfrom America.
是你父亲，Windemere 先生
It's your father, Mr Windemere.
现在不行
Not now.
我来接，他会担心的
No, I'll take it.He'll worry.
- 我爱你- 我爱你
- I love you.- I love you.
一个女人送来这个
And a woman brought this.
她在楼下等
She's waiting downstairs.
谢谢
Thank you.
你在这里干嘛?我们有协议
What are you doing here?We had an agreement.
我回来还扇子
I came to return the fan.
你太太今早怎么样?
How is your wifefeeling this morning?
你不许靠近我太太10尺
You don't get within ten feetof my wife.
我只是问候她
I only asked how she was.
如果你来这告诉她你是谁...
If you're here to tellher who you are...
还是我来吧
it's better coming from me.
是我的秘密，不是你的
It's my secret, not yours.
你保守的很好
You've kept it very well.
20年是个很久的时间
Twenty years is a long time.
没造成什么伤害
It doesn't seem to have beentoo much of a strain.
你看个小女孩...
You see a little girl...
合适的岁数把想法放在一边
the right age,you push the thought aside.
关上门
Close the door.
只在三点……
Only at three o'clock,that in-between hour...
干什么都晚了，吃饭有太早...
too late to do anything,too early for dinner...
门大敞着
doors come flying open.
我不觉得你对她有感情
I don't believe you feelanything for her.
你只顾自己，没别人
You care about yourself,and no-one else.
Robert.
你父亲要跟你说话，很重要
Your father needs to talk to you,he says it's important.
Erlynne太太来还你扇子
Mrs Erlynnecame to return your fan.
她刚要走
She was just leaving.
不，别走，我要跟你说话
No, don't leave, I need tospeak with you.
- 她会耽误航班- 就一会儿
- She'll miss her plane.- Just a few minutes.
你父亲在等你接电话，说是重要事
Your father's waiting on the phone.He said it's important.
误航班...
It would be a great mistake...
会是个大错
to miss your plane.
我来确认你安全到家了
I came to make sureyou got home safely.
你还不能走
You can't leave yet.
你是证明没事发生的唯一证人
You're my only witness thatnothing happened.
你的证人?
Your witness?
我要告诉他真相
I'm going to tell him the truth.
你做错了
What you did is your mistake.
你的麻烦，你来扛吧
Your sack of bricks. You carry it.
你不能忏悔后把痛苦留给爱你的人
You don't confess and had it offto someone who loves you.
但所有人都觉得你...
But everybody thinksyou were having...
他们反正要那么想，没关系
They'll think it anyway.It doesn't matter.
那不是真相，对Tuppy来说有关系
That's not true,it matters to Tuppy.
我无法对毁了你们的婚约熟视无睹
I can't be responsiblefor ruining that.
你想把我做过的唯一善举给毁了吗?
You wanna spoil the onegood thing I've ever done?
告诉他真相是对的
It's only right to tell himthe truth.
你们相爱，这就是事实
You love each other!That's your truth.
你干嘛放弃一段好婚姻而拯救我?
Why you giving up your chanceof marriage to save mine?
- 没道理- 我告诉你真相
- It doesn't make any sense.- I'll tell you the truth.
但首先答应我...
But first, promise you're notgoing to make...
不会去做大忏悔
some grand confession.
以圣名起誓
Swear it on whatever youhold sacred.
我以我母亲起誓
I swear on my mother.
什么?
Pardon?
她是我的守护天使
She's my guardian angel.
我的一生，都想象她那样
My whole life, I've wantedto be like her.
我确信她不想你以她为标准
I'm sure she wouldn't hold youto such a standard.
她此时一定以我为耻
She'd be so ashamed of me now.
我们都在深渊挣扎，Windemere太太
We all straddle the abyss,Mrs Windemere.
如果我们不下望又怎能知道自己的真相?
If we never look down, how canwe know who we are?
母亲永远也不会因不堕落的女儿为耻
A mother could never be ashamedof a daughter who didn't fall in.
我希望你对
I hope you're right.
我从未如此确信过
I've never been more certainof anything.
我发誓
I swear, them.
你要告诉我什么?
What is it you wanted to tell me?
没事
Nothing.
我要耽误航班了
I'll miss my plane.
再见， Windemere太太
Goodbye, Mrs Windemere.
我希望我们再见
I hope we meet again.
我也是
So do I.
Erlynne太太
Mrs Erlynne.
- 你没告诉她吧?- 没有
- You didn't tell her?- No.
为什么?
Why not?
她有母亲
She has a mother.
小盒里的照片
A photograph in a locket.
那是个神话
It's a fairy tale.
一个善良、温存的妈妈，爱她，照顾她
A kind, caring mother, who lovesand watches over her.
我不能把那个带走
I'm not going to take that away.
你也不该
And neither should you.
Erlynne太太,1000美元
Mrs Erlynne,One thousand Dollars.
有一晚，我觉得你爱上了其他女人
For one night I thought you were inlove with another woman.
有一晚我以为你爱上了其他男人
For one night I thought you were inlove with another man.
- 她是对的- 谁?
- She was right.- Who?
Erlynne太太说我们不该对...
Mrs Erlynne said we can'tshut our eyes...
不完美熟视无睹...
to everything that isn't perfect...
否则我们会坠入深渊
otherwise we might fallinto a huge abyss.
我们差一点
We almost fell.
她是个聪明的女人
She's a smart woman.
她是个好女人
She's a good woman.
比我想的好
Better than I thought.
她很坚持
She insisted.
谁?
Who?
Meg，一个对她的念想
Meg.Something to remember her by.
而且她解释了一切
And she explained everything.
一切?
Everything?
哦，对，当然瘪轮胎，狗
Oh, yes, couse.The flat tyre, the dog.
巴西出租车司机和怀孕的女儿……
The Brazilian taxi diver with thepregnant daughter...
丢了钱包
who lost her purse.
而我的辩解是...
And the only thing I can sayin my defense is...
我没什么可辩解的
that I have no defense.
我跳到结论，直接往最坏想
I jumped to conclusions andthought the worst.
这破筐往哪去?
Where's this old crate going to?
我不知道
I don't know.
到地方后你会嫁给我吗?
Will you marry me when get there?
男人娶该娶的女人为妻
A man gets the wife he deserves.
而我，可是一个很坏很坏的男人
Well, I've been a very, very bad man.
你知道，John,爱是战场
You know, John,love's a battleground.
而那只是皮肉之伤
It was only a flesh wound.
男人预支，女人隐忍
Men advance,women resist.
我们退缩他们就堵住我们的退路
We retreat and theyblock our escape.
我们不能赢的
We can't win.
两性无法彼此理解
The sexes will never understandeach other.
他们以伤彼此伤害
Only because they take such painsto deceive each other.
哦，Dumby,你醒着吗?
Oh, hello Dumby,are you awake?
我赢了吗?
Am I winning?